Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're going to be going to one of those places that is really common, right?
今天我们要去一个非常常见的地方，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
We're going to the hair salon.
我们要去美发沙龙。
The hair salon or maybe also called a barber shop.
美发沙龙，或者也叫理发店。
I guess in this case it's a barber shop because it's a man who's getting his hair cut.
我想这次是理发店，因为是一个男人在剪头发。
Okay, so before we see what happens in this barber shop, let's take a look at some of
好的，在我们看理发店里发生了什么之前，先来看看一些
the vocabulary we might encounter in Vocabulary Preview.
在词汇预览中可能会遇到的词汇。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, we're going to look at two words that you'll hear in this dialogue.
好的，我们要看两个你会在对话中听到的词。
And the first one is trim.
第一个是trim。
Trim.
Trim。
A trim.
修剪。
All right, so when you trim something.
好的，当你修剪某物时。
You cut just a little bit of it.
你只剪掉一点点。
All right, so if I go to the hair salon to get a trim.
好的，所以如果我去美发沙龙修剪头发。
You are going to cut only a little bit of your hair.
你只会剪掉一点点头发。
Okay.
好的。
You're not going to change the style and make it look different.
你不会改变发型，让它看起来不一样。
Okay, so a trim.
好的，所以是修剪。
And I think here we've seen that it can be a verb and a noun, right?
我想这里我们看到它可以是动词和名词，对吧？
Okay, so I'm going to get a trim.
好的，所以我要去修剪一下。
Yes.
是的。
Or I want you to trim my hair.
或者我想让你修剪我的头发。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
And what about our next word?
那下一个词呢？
Fancy.
Fancy。
So fancy.
很花哨。
Now, we know that this word maybe is related to something like luxury.
现在，我们知道这个词可能和奢华有关。
Or formal or something like that.
或者正式之类的。
Right.
对。
So in this case or in this context, we're going to be using it a little bit different.
所以在这种情况下或这个语境中，我们会稍微不同地使用它。
That's right.
没错。
Here in this dialogue, we'll hear nothing too fancy.
在这个对话中，我们会听到“不要太花哨”。
Or nothing too complicated.
或者不要太复杂。
Nothing too different.
不要太特别。
Okay.
好的。
So we don't want anything too fancy.
所以我们不想要太花哨的东西。
All right.
好的。
With these two words in mind, I think we're ready to listen to the dialogue.
记住这两个词，我想我们可以听对话了。
Hello there.
你好啊。
Come on in.
进来吧。
Don't just stand there.
别光站在那儿。
Come and take a seat.
过来坐下。
Okay.
好的。
Well, I just want a trim.
嗯，我只想修剪一下。
Nothing too fancy.
不要太花哨。
Oh my gosh.
哦，天哪。
Your hair is amazing.
你的头发太棒了。
So silky.
这么柔顺。
So shiny.
这么有光泽。
I am going to work my magic on your hair.
我要在你的头发上施展我的魔法。
You hear me?
听到了吗？
You are going to look like a million bucks.
你会看起来帅呆了。
Okay.
好的。
Can you make sure my sideburns are even?
你能确保我的鬓角整齐吗？
And you just take a little at the top.
还有顶上只剪一点点。
Don't you worry.
别担心。
I'll take care of everything.
我会处理好一切的。
Oh my God.
哦，天哪。
I just love your curly hair.
我太喜欢你的卷发了。
It's so fluffy and cute.
它又蓬松又可爱。
You should totally let it grow out.
你真该让它留长。
An afro would look great on you.
爆炸头会很适合你。
Um, no.
嗯，不要。
Okay.
好的。
But you are going to be my masterpiece.
但你会成为我的杰作。
Okay, so I think maybe his haircut is not quite what he expected.
好的，所以我想他的发型可能不是他期望的那样。
I think he trusted the stylist a little bit too much.
我觉得他太信任发型师了。
I think the stylist had too many Red Bulls or something.
我觉得发型师喝了太多红牛之类的。
He was very hyper.
他太亢奋了。
Maybe that was his problem.
也许那就是他的问题。
All right.
好的。
So why don't we take a look now at some of the language that we saw in Language Takeaway.
那我们来看看语言要点中的一些语言点吧。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So I guess the stylist really thought this guy had nice hair, right?
所以我想发型师真的觉得这家伙头发不错，对吧？
Yeah, we heard how he described his hair.
是的，我们听到他描述他的头发。
He said it was so silky.
他说它很柔顺。
Silky.
柔顺。
All right.
好的。
So we know the word silk, a material, very soft and smooth material.
所以我们知道silk这个词，一种材料，非常柔软光滑的材料。
And when something is silky, it's very soft and smooth.
当某物是silky时，它非常柔软光滑。
All right.
好的。
So silky hair.
所以是柔顺的头发。
Or silky skin.
或者柔滑的皮肤。
All right.
好的。
So silky.
所以是柔顺。
So he said he had silky and shiny hair.
所以他说他有柔顺有光泽的头发。
Shiny.
有光泽。
All right.
好的。
So we know what shiny is.
所以我们知道有光泽是什么意思。
Do we?
是吗？
Yes, we do.
是的，我们知道。
Okay, what?
好的，是什么？
So something that is shiny is you can see yourself in it.
所以有光泽的东西是你能在里面看到自己。
Like gold is shiny.
比如金子是有光泽的。
Or silver is shiny.
或者银子是有光泽的。
All right.
好的。
Or if you look in the back of a CD, it's shiny.
或者如果你看CD的背面，它是有光泽的。
Yeah.
是的。
So the light bounces off things that are shiny.
所以光线会从有光泽的东西上反射。
All right.
好的。
Now, getting into more hairstyle vocabulary, he wanted to make sure that his sideburns
现在，进入更多发型词汇，他想确保他的鬓角
were even.
是整齐的。
Sideburns.
鬓角。
All right.
好的。
So sideburns.
所以是鬓角。
All right.
好的。
Well, sideburns are things that men have, right?
嗯，鬓角是男人有的东西，对吧？
All right.
好的。
Women don't have sideburns.
女人没有鬓角。
No.
没有。
Okay.
好的。
So sideburns are the hair that grows on your cheeks near your ears.
所以鬓角是长在你脸颊靠近耳朵的头发。
Okay.
好的。
Those are your sideburns.
那些就是你的鬓角。
Yes.
是的。
And now also, the hair stylist suggested that he should let his hair grow out.
现在还有，发型师建议他应该让头发留长。
Grow out.
留长。
Let your hair grow out.
让你的头发留长。
All right.
好的。
So what does that mean exactly?
那到底是什么意思？
Let your hair get longer.
让你的头发变长。
So you can say, let your hair grow.
所以你可以说，让你的头发长。
Yeah.
是的。
But I guess it's more common to hear, let your hair grow out.
但我想更常听到的是，让你的头发留长。
Well, maybe it just means something a little bit different.
嗯，也许意思有点不同。
If I let my hair grow, I might let it grow a little bit.
如果我让头发长，我可能让它长一点。
It might get a little bit longer.
它可能会变长一点。
But if I let my hair grow out, maybe it's short now and I'll let it get really long.
但如果我让头发留长，也许现在很短，我会让它变得很长。
Okay.
好的。
So to let your hair grow out is to really change the length.
所以让头发留长就是真正改变长度。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So let your hair grow out.
所以是让头发留长。
And our last word on language takeaway today, afro.
今天语言要点的最后一个词，afro。
Afro.
Afro。
So if this guy let his curly hair grow out, he would have an afro.
所以如果这家伙让他的卷发留长，他就会有一个爆炸头。
An afro, right?
爆炸头，对吧？
So now this hairstyle was very popular in the seventies.
所以这种发型在七十年代很流行。
That's right.
没错。
It's like a big, round, curly, fluffy ball of hair.
它就像一个又大又圆又卷又蓬松的头发球。
Exactly.
正是。
So that's an afro.
那就是爆炸头。
We'll post some pictures on the website for you to get a clear idea of what this looks
我们会在网站上贴一些图片，让你清楚了解它长什么样。
like.
像这样。
All right.
好的。
So I think now we are ready to listen to our dialogue for the second time, and then we'll
所以我想现在我们准备好听第二遍对话了，然后我们会
come back and look at some phrases.
回来看一些短语。
Hello there.
你好啊。
Come on in.
进来吧。
Don't just stand there.
别光站在那儿。
Come and take a seat.
过来坐下。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
Well, I just want to trim.
嗯，我只想修剪一下。
Nothing too fancy.
不要太花哨。
Oh my gosh.
哦，天哪。
Your hair is amazing.
你的头发太棒了。
So silky.
这么柔顺。
So shiny.
这么有光泽。
I am going to work my magic on your hair.
我要在你的头发上施展我的魔法。
You hear me?
听到了吗？
You are going to look like a million bucks.
你会看起来帅呆了。
Okay.
好的。
Um, can you make sure my sideburns are even and you just take a little off the top?
嗯，你能确保我的鬓角整齐，顶上只剪一点点吗？
Don't you worry.
别担心。
I'll take care of everything.
我会处理好一切的。
Oh my God.
哦，天哪。
I just love your curly hair.
我太喜欢你的卷发了。
It's so fluffy and cute.
它又蓬松又可爱。
You should totally let it grow out.
你真该让它留长。
An afro would look great on you.
爆炸头会很适合你。
Um, no.
嗯，不要。
Okay.
好的。
You're going to be my masterpiece.
你会成为我的杰作。
Okay.
好的。
So we have some phrases here that you might hear in a hair salon or in a barber shop.
所以我们有一些你可能会在美发沙龙或理发店听到的短语。
So why don't we look at those now in Fluency Builder.
那我们来看看流利度构建中的这些短语吧。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
The hairstylist said, don't just stand there.
发型师说，别光站在那儿。
Don't just stand there.
别光站在那儿。
All right.
好的。
Don't just stand there.
别光站在那儿。
So this is an interesting phrase, Marco.
所以这是一个有趣的短语，Marco。
I mean, it's made up of really simple words, right?
我的意思是，它由非常简单的词组成，对吧？
Right.
对。
But actually those words make it in order that's a little bit different.
但实际上这些词的顺序有点不同。
So why don't we hear a few examples to help us understand how to use this phrase.
所以我们来听几个例子，帮助我们理解如何使用这个短语。
Example one.
例子一。
Don't just stand there.
别光站在那儿。
Help me take these boxes into the house.
帮我把这些箱子搬进屋里。
Example two.
例子二。
The house is on fire.
房子着火了。
Don't just stand there.
别光站在那里。
Call the fire department.
快打电话给消防队。
Example three.
例子三。
Don't just stand there in the rain.
别光站在雨里。
Come inside.
快进来。
Okay.
好的。
So basically we can understand that if somebody tells you don't just stand there, they are
所以基本上我们可以理解，如果有人对你说“别光站在那里”，他们
expecting you to do something.
是希望你做点什么。
We might use this phrase when somebody is not doing what we think they should do.
当别人没有做我们认为他们该做的事时，我们可能会用这个短语。
Okay.
好的。
When action is required.
当需要采取行动时。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So why don't we move on to our next phrase now?
那我们继续下一个短语吧？
Look like a million bucks.
看起来像百万美元。
You look like a million bucks.
你看起来像百万美元。
So when someone looks like a million bucks, they look really, really good.
所以当一个人看起来像百万美元时，他们看起来非常非常棒。
Yeah.
是的。
So that is a very common way of just saying you look very good.
这是一种很常见的说法，意思就是你看起来很好看。
Or something looks like a million bucks.
或者某样东西看起来像百万美元。
So it can be for a person or a thing, right?
所以它可以用于人或物，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
And our final phrase.
还有我们最后一个短语。
And this one is really common in barber shops.
这个在理发店里很常见。
Take a little off the top.
上面稍微剪一点。
So that basically means cut a little bit on top.
所以这基本上就是上面剪短一点的意思。
Exactly.
没错。
And now can I say take a little off the sides?
那我能说“两边稍微剪一点”吗？
Yeah.
可以。
You can say that as well.
你也可以这么说。
Alright.
好的。
So take a little off the top.
所以“上面稍微剪一点”。
Take a little off the sides.
“两边稍微剪一点”。
Okay.
好的。
So with all this great hair cutting language, why don't we listen to our dialogue one last
既然我们已经学了这么多关于理发的用语，不如最后再听一遍我们的对话吧？
time?
时间？
Hello there.
你好啊。
Come on in.
请进。
Don't just stand there.
别光站在那儿。
Come and take a seat.
过来坐下吧。
Okay.
好的。
Well, I just want to trim.
嗯，我只是想修一下。
Nothing too fancy.
不要太花哨。
Oh my gosh.
哦，天哪。
Your hair is amazing.
你的头发太棒了。
So silky, so shiny.
这么柔顺，这么有光泽。
I am going to work my magic on your hair.
我要在你的头发上施展我的魔法。
You hear me?
你听到了吗？
You are going to look like a million bucks.
你会看起来像百万美元一样。
Okay.
好的。
Can you make sure my sideburns are even and you just take a little off the top?
你能确保我的鬓角整齐，头顶只剪一点点吗？
Don't you worry.
别担心。
I'll take care of everything.
我会处理好一切的。
Oh my God.
哦，我的天。
I just love your curly hair.
我就是喜欢你的卷发。
It's so fluffy and cute.
它这么蓬松又可爱。
You should totally let it grow out.
你真该让它留长。
An afro would look great on you.
爆炸头会很适合你。
Um, no.
嗯，不要。
Okay.
好的。
But you are going to be my masterpiece.
但你会成为我的杰作。
All right, so now talking about hairstyles and different types of hair, there are some
好了，现在说到发型和不同类型的头发，有一些
interesting ones that maybe aren't so fashionable anymore, right?
有趣的发型可能已经不那么时尚了，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
Actually, English has a lot of really cool words to describe haircuts.
实际上，英语中有很多很酷的词来形容发型。
So let's start with a couple of them.
那我们先从几个开始吧。
For example, a mullet.
比如，鲻鱼头。
A mullet.
鲻鱼头。
So this is when your hair is really short on top and really long in the back.
就是头顶头发很短，后面头发很长的发型。
Right.
对。
So the sides and the top are really short, but the back, you have long hair.
所以两侧和顶部很短，但后面有长发。
Yeah.
是的。
In Canada, we call that a shorty shorty long back.
在加拿大，我们叫它“短短长背头”。
Shorty shorty long back.
短短长背头。
Yeah.
是啊。
We also call it hockey hair.
我们也叫它冰球头。
Hockey hair.
冰球头。
Or even all business up front, all party behind.
或者甚至叫“前面正经，后面派对”。
Well, Canadians are obviously very into this hairstyle.
嗯，加拿大人显然很喜欢这种发型。
It's unfortunately true.
不幸的是，这是真的。
All right.
好吧。
We also have, for example, a mohawk.
我们还有，比如说，莫西干头。
Hmm.
嗯。
Popular amongst the punk rock kids.
在朋克摇滚青年中很流行。
Exactly.
没错。
So you shave your head on the sides, but you leave a little like stripe of long hair on
所以你把两边头发剃光，但留一条长头发在
top.
头顶。
Of sticking up long hair.
竖起来的长头发。
Okay.
好的。
And that's a mohawk.
那就是莫西干头。
What about a flat top?
那平头呢？
Oh, popular with law enforcement agents and serial killers.
哦，在执法人员和连环杀手中很流行。
So basically it's short hair on the sides.
所以基本上就是两边头发短。
And short and flat hair on the top.
头顶头发又短又平。
Right.
对。
So your hair...
所以你的头发...
Kind of looks like a box.
看起来像个盒子。
Right.
对。
Like a box haircut.
像个盒子发型。
I do not have a flat top for all of you out there.
我可没有平头，各位。
But I did used to have a crew cut.
但我以前留过板寸。
Oh, crew cut.
哦，板寸。
A crew cut.
板寸。
Yeah.
是啊。
Like an army haircut.
像军队发型。
Right.
对。
So very short on the sides and a little bit long on top.
所以两边很短，头顶稍微长一点。
Yeah.
是啊。
Okay.
好的。
And our last one, my actual personal least favorite haircut.
最后一种，我个人最不喜欢的发型。
Dreadlocks.
脏辫。
All right.
好吧。
So dreadlocks are like knots of hair, right?
所以脏辫就是像头发打结，对吧？
Yeah.
是啊。
Like you haven't washed your hair in about seven years.
就像你大概七年没洗头一样。
Right.
没错。
Those are dreadlocks.
那些是脏辫。
Very popular among Rastafarian.
在拉斯塔法里教徒中很流行。
Sure.
当然。
Or like young hippie kids.
或者像年轻的嬉皮士小孩。
Yeah.
嗯。
Hippies, right?
嬉皮士，对吧？
Yeah.
对。
Very good.
很好。
So what about in your countries?
那你们国家呢？
What different hairstyles are popular there?
那里流行什么不同的发型？
I know that Japanese hairstyles are really cool.
我知道日本发型真的很酷。
Yeah.
是啊。
That's right.
没错。
Japanese haircuts can be pretty awesome.
日本发型可以相当棒。
Right.
对。
So tell us all about it.
那就跟我们说说吧。
Come to our website.
来我们的网站。
Post some pictures.
上传一些照片。
And also if you have any questions or doubts, let us know.
另外，如果你们有任何问题或疑惑，告诉我们。
Well, thanks for downloading this lesson, you guys.
好了，感谢下载这节课，各位。
And until next time, goodbye.
下次再见，拜拜。